goatsontheroad.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy - Goats On The Road

**GOATS ON THE ROAD PRIVACY POLICY:**

This privacy policy sets out how Goats On The Road uses and protects any information that you give Goats On The Road when you use this website.

Goats On The Road is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Goats On The Road may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from Nov 06, 2017.

Please note that **Goats On The Road is a travel blog, not a multi-national corporation.** Most of the data that is collected on this website is automatic or done in the background. The only time we’d have your personal data (Like name and email address) is if you manually entered it into the site somewhere. We are not in the business of taking information or data from our users. The only reason our website takes any data at all is to help us better serve you.

If you’re worried about us using your data incorrectly, or selling it to a third-party like Facebook and other large companies have been accused of doing, that’s not the case. We only use the data you give us freely and are not trying to get any information from you that doesn’t help us serve you better.

Our website (like almost all websites online today) will store cookies in your browser. These cookies can not only help your user experience, but they also allow us to earn commissions through our affiliate partners.

When we recommend a product and you click the link and make a purchase, sometimes (not always) we are rewarded with a commission. These transactions will NEVER cost you an extra cent and in many cases, you actually receive a discount for using our links. Cookies are what make this possible, so by allowing our website to use cookies, you’re actually helping keep this site running. Without cookies, we wouldn’t make any commissions and therefore wouldn’t be able to offer so much amazing content for free.

## What we collect

We may collect the following information:

  * name and blog URL
  * email address (Only with your consent)
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers when user is prompted
  * Google Analytics tracking data (anonymous data that we use to see how many people visit our site)

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact forms

When you enter your email to contact us, we are automatically given your email so that we can reply. We will not use the email to send you any promotional emails, only to reply to whatever questions you have and we will not send more emails unless our email conversation continues. We use a plugin to embed our contact form, which tells us the email you entered so that we can reply.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to track the visitors on this site so that we know how many people we have visiting our blog.

### Email Newsletters

The only time that we actually use your email to send you a message is if you request that we do so. On this blog, you will see optin forms that ask for your first name and email address. If you do choose to enter this information, we will send you an emails including whatever special offer you requested, as well as some emails to help you travel, earn money from travel or save money for travel. We NEVER share your email with anyone and you can unsubscribe from all of our emails at any time.

## What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided. ONLY when you have opted in to receive these emails.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. This is just so that we can better provide you with the best travel advice and travel products.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you’ve entered your email to receive our newsletter or a free product (ie: our free ebooks), then we will keep that data until you unsubscribe from our lists, or until we feel that we’re not serving you any more. If you haven’t expressed interest in our emails for 90 days or more, we may delete your information entirely from our email servers.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

We don’t send your data to any third-party or sell your data, however, when you leave a comment, it may be checked through an automated spam detection service called Askimet. You may find their Privacy Policy here: https://akismet.com/tos/. Also, if you have entered your email to our site, we may use your email address to also send you offers and information on Facebook, Instagram and the Facebook ads network.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Our website is 100% secure and we work hard to keep your data secure.

## How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.  
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

We do kindly ask you to allow us to use cookies on this website. It’s the only way we’re able to track our affiliate commissions, which make up a large part of how we make money on this site. Without cookies, this site would not be sustainable. So we appreciate your support greatly by accepting cookies.

## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * Whenever you sign up for an email through our popups and optin forms on this site, you will receive emails from us. You can opt-out of these emails at any time. Every email we send has an unsubscribe link at the bottom.
  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen. This website automatically stores cookies on your browser. Many of these cookies allow us to receive a commission from our affiliate partners which in turn helps us to keep this website running. We do appreciate if you keep your cookies on.

We are a travel blog, not a large company. The only time we have access to your email or contact information is if you add it into our website manually. We would never try to get your personal information for any other reason besides emailing you great travel advice and new cool travel products, courses and ebooks that we create… for you.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Box 8 Site 11 RR1, High River AB, Canada T1V1N1.  
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us ([[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)) as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
